Guide to the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations oral history collection 2011.019
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Amalia della Paolera, 2013 Dec 30; 2014 March 20; 2011.019.088
  Argentina; Cultural diversity; Education |z New York (State) |z New York; Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.); Interethnic marriage; Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Presbyterian Church |z New York (State) |z Kings County; School sports |z New York (State) |z New York
- Daisy Dominguez, 2012 July 6; 2011.019.038
  Daisy Dominguez was born to Ecuadorian parents in New York City and raised in the Bushwick neighborhood of Brooklyn. Dominguez received a B.A. in Latin American studies from New York University, an M.L.S. from Long Island University, and an M.A. in history from the City College of New York, all located in New York City. She worked as an English language teacher in Quito, Ecuador and a reference librarian at City College of New York.
  In the interview, Dominguez discusses her cultural and racial identities; childhood in the Bushwick neighborhood of Brooklyn; trips to Ecuador; and study of the Quechua language. Interview conducted by Cynthia Tobar.
  Bushwick (New York, N.Y.); Ecuadorian Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Ethnic identity; Quechua language; Quito (Ecuador); Race identity; United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Jessica Chen Drammeh, 2012 May 20; 2011.019.031
  Jessica Chen Drammeh was born to a Chinese mother and a mixed heritage American father and raised in Wheeling, West Virginia. Drammeh received a B.F.A. in film and television production from New York University in New York City. She directed and produced "Anomaly," a documentary film about mixed race Americans.
  In the interview, Drammeh discusses her childhood; Chinese heritage; incidents of racially-motivated bullying; mother's death; impressions of community identity in the the Boerum Hill, Fort Greene, and Prospect Heights neighborhoods of Brooklyn; involvement in the mixed race community; and production of her documentary film, "Anomaly." Interview conducted by Rita Renedo.
  Boerum Hill (New York, N.Y.); Bullying in schools |z West Virginia |z Wheeling; Chinese Americans |z West Virginia |z Wheeling; Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Documentary films; Education, Higher |z New York (State) |z New York; Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.); Prospect Heights (New York, N.Y.); Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; United States |x Emigration and immigration; Wheeling (W. Va.)
- Yasmin Dwedar, 2014 March 20; 2011.019.083
  Yasmin Dwedar was born to a Filipino Catholic mother and an Egyptian Muslim father and raised in Brooklyn, New York. Dwedar received a B.A. in English language arts from Hunter College, an M.A. in international studies from the Graduate Center at City University of New York, and a J.D. from the City University of New York School of Law, all located in New York City. She worked as a lawyer in New York City.
  In the interview, Dwedar discusses her ethnic and religious identities; educational experiences; parents' courtship and marriage; mother's conversion to Islam; family visits to Egypt; and experiences with Islamophobia in high school. Interview conducted by Amna Ahmad.
  Bay Ridge (New York, N.Y); Conversion |x Islam; Education |z New York (State) |z New York; Egypt; Egyptians |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Female circumcision; Filipinos |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Interfaith families; Islamophobia; Lawyers |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Muslims |z New York (State) |z New York; United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Shawn Elgart, 2011 November 18; 2011.019.001
  Shawn Elgart was born to African American parents in Fort Worth, Texas and raised in Fort Worth and Portland, Oregon. Elgart received a B.A. in psychology from San Diego State University in California and an M.S.Ed. in childhood education from Hunter College in New York City.
  In the interview, Elgart discusses her interracial and interfaith marriage; childhood experiences in a single-parent household; conversion to Judaism; daughter's relationship with extended family members; and mother's adolescent years and early adulthood. Interview conducted by April Reynosa.
  African American Jews |z New York (State) |z New York; African Americans |z Oregon |z Portland; Conversion |x Judaism; Education, Higher |z California |z San Diego; Interfaith marriage; Parenthood; Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Portland (Or.); Racially mixed families
- Monica Elias and Roy Walter, 2013 August 14; 2011.019.051
  Monica Elias was born to an Ashkenazi Jewish mother and a Sephardic Jewish father and raised in New York City. Elias received a B.F.A. in painting from Wesleyan University in Middletown, Connecticut and an M.A. in speech language pathology from New York University in New York City. She worked as a speech language pathologist for the New York City Department of Education and in private practice.
  Roy Walter was born to an English mother and a German American father and raised in Northport, New York. Walter received a B.S. in music performance and theory and studied computer science at Brooklyn College in New York City. He worked in the media and entertainment industries.
  In the interviews, Elias and Walter both discuss their childhoods; cultural and religious heritage; courtship and marriage; experiences as an interfaith couple; and the decision to raise their children in the Jewish faith. Interviews conducted by Abigail Ettelman.
  Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.); Education |z New York (State) |z New York; Education, Higher |z Connecticut |z Middletown; Interfaith families; Jews, Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Judaism; Parenthood; Religion
- Champ Ensminger, 2014 February 2; 2011.019.077
  Champ Ensminger was born to a Thai mother and a French father in Chiang Mai, Thailand and raised in Spokane, Washington. Ensminger received a B.A. in cinema studies and anthropology from the University of Washington at Seattle.
  In the interview, Ensminger discusses his racial identity; French and Thai heritage; romantic relationships; parents' marriage and divorce; mother’s remarriage; relationship with his German American stepfather; experience reuniting with his father's family in France as an adult; and involvement in the artistic community in New York City. Interview conducted by Kendra Danowski.
  Artists |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Chiang Mai (Thailand); Education, Higher |z Washington (State) |z Seattle; France; Race identity; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Spokane (Wash.); Thais |z Washington (State) |z Spokane; United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Sebastien Fargeat and Vanessa Snowden, 2012 April 11; 2011.019.026
  Sebastien Fargeat was born to French parents in Lyon, France. Fargeat attended Université Jean Moulin in Lyon, France for a graduate degree in international security policies. He worked in the tourism industry in New York City.
  Vanessa Snowden was born to a Venezuelan mother and a white American father in Caracas, Venezuela and raised in Buffalo, New York. Snowden received a B.A. in English from Princeton University in New Jersey and an M.S. in adolescent education from Pace University in New York City. She worked as an au pair and teaching assistant in Lyon, France, and as a middle and high school teacher in New York City.
  In the interview, Snowden and Fargeat discuss their courtship and marriage; visa application process in the United States; and the cultural and language barriers they experienced in Venezuela, France, and the United States. Snowden also discusses her experiences in college; teaching in New York City; and working with an economically and culturally diverse student body. Interview conducted by Charis Shafer.
  East Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.); French |z New York (State) |z New York; Lyon (France); Racially mixed families; Racism in education |z New York (State) |z New York; Teachers |z New York (State) |z New York; United States |x Emigration and immigration; Venezuela; Venezuelan Americans |z New York (State)
- Caroline Fermin, 2013 March 1; 2011.019.042
  Caroline Fermin was born to a white American mother and a Dominican father in Houston, Texas and raised in New Orleans, Louisiana. Fermin studied dance at the New Orleans Center for the Creative Arts and received a B.F.A. in dance from the Juilliard School in New York City. She lived in the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn and worked as a professional dancer and dance teacher.
  In the interview, Fermin discusses her racial identity; dance education and practice; spiritual and religious beliefs; family's mixed heritage; father's experiences with racial profiling and prejudice in New Orleans; and racial dynamics within her extended family. Interview conducted by Liza Zapol.
  Catholicism; Dancers |z New York (State) |z New York; Dominican Americans; Education |z Louisiana |z New Orleans; Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.); Interracial marriage; New Orleans (La.); Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Spirituality
- Joseph Figueroa, 2012 June 12; 2011.019.037
  Joseph Figueroa was born to Puerto Rican parents and raised in Brooklyn, New York. Figueroa earned a high school diploma while incarcerated in prison. After his release, Figueroa worked for gang intervention organizations and lived in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn.
  In the interview, Figueroa discusses his childhood in the Brownsville neighborhood of Brooklyn; impressions of racial tensions in Brownsville; experience dropping out of high school and joining a gang; impressions of jail and halfway houses; and work with at-risk youth. Interview conducted by Dorothy Saint Jean.
  Brownsville (New York, N.Y.); Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.); Drug traffic |z New York (State) |z New York; Prison gangs |z New York (State); Prison |z New York (State); Puerto Ricans |z New York (State) |z Kings County
- Ricardo Osmondo Francis, 2014 June 13; 2011.019.101
  Ricardo Osmondo Francis was born to an African American mother and a Panamanian father in Houston, Texas. He was raised in Los Angeles, California and Houston, where he attended the High School for the Performing and Visual Arts. He received a B.F.A. in painting from the Maryland Institute College of Art in Baltimore. Francis founded Apanamae Productions, an independent art company, and worked as director of the LeonidesArts NY Gallery in New York City.
  In the interview, Francis discusses his childhood; participation in the Singing Boys of Houston choir; formal arts education; involvement in the artistic community; perspectives on racism and homophobia; mother's adoption; and maternal grandmother's sentiments on race and racism. Interview conducted by Rebecca Jacobs.
  Adoption; African Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Artists |z New York (State) |z New York; Homophobia; Houston (Tex.); Panamanians |z Texas |z Houston; Queer identity
- Fiona Gardner and Uche Nduka, 2013 June 5; 2011.019.048
  Fiona Gardner was born to white American parents with Romanian and German Jewish heritage and raised in St. Paul, Minnesota. Gardner received a B.F.A. in painting from the Rhode Island School of Design in Providence and an M.F.A. from Columbia University in New York City. She worked as a photographer and artist in Boston, Massachusetts and New York City.
  Uche Nduka was born to Igbo parents in Umuahia, Nigeria. Nduka received a B.A. in English and history from the University of Nigeria in Nsukka. He lived in Bremen, Germany and Amsterdam, The Netherlands, and received an M.F.A. in creative writing from Long Island University in Brooklyn. He worked as a writer and an adjunct college lecturer in literature in New York City.
  In the interviews, Gardner and Nduka discuss their childhoods; educational experiences; courtship; and living in Brooklyn. Gardner discusses her childhood in an observant Jewish household. Nduka discusses the Nigerian Civil War of 1967-1970; genocide of the Igbo people; and British cultural influence on Nigeria. Interviews conducted by Charis Shafer.
  Education |z Nigeria; Genocide |x Igbo (African people); Igbo (African people) |z Nigeria; Interracial dating; Judaism; Nigeria; Nigeria |x History |x Civil War, 1967-1970; Race identity; Saint Paul (Minn.); United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Douglas Giles and Natalie Giles, 2012 January 14; 2012 January 22; 2012.01.14.22
  Natalie Green Giles was born to white American Jewish parents in New York City and raised in Queens, New York. Natalie received a B.A. in psychology from Williams College in Williamstown, Massachusetts and an M.P.P.M. from the Yale School of Management in New Haven, Connecticut. She worked in the Office of the Mayor of New York City under the Giuliani administration and as an independent writing and development consultant.
  Douglas Giles was born to white American Christian parents in Chicago, Illinois and raised in Greenbrae, California. Douglas received an undergraduate degree from the University of Oregon and an M.P.P.M. from the Yale School of Management in New Haven, Connecticut. He worked for KPMG, a consulting organization.
  In the interviews, Natalie and Douglas Giles discuss their courtship and marriage; interfaith relationship; and raising children in the Brooklyn, New York. Natalie discusses her childhood in Queens, New York; German Jewish ancestry; and maternal grandparents' flight from Nazi Germany. Douglas's discusses his childhood in San Francisco, California; and relatives who worked as blue collar steelworkers in the 19th century and business owners in the 20th century. Interviews conducted by Abigail Ettelman.
  Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.); Episcopalians |z California |z San Francisco; Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945); Interfaith families; Interfaith marriage; Jews, Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Judaism; Parenthood; Religious identity; San Francisco (Calif.)
- Zoltan Gluck, 2014 May 29; 2011.019.094
  Zoltan Gluck was born to a mixed race American mother and a Hungarian father in San Francisco, California. Glück received a B.A. in philosophy from Bard College in Annandale-on-Hudson, New York and an M.A. in sociology and social anthropology from Central European University in Budapest, Hungary. Gluck moved to New York City to pursue a Ph.D. in anthropology at the Graduate Center at City University of New York.
  In the interview, Gluck discusses his Mexican, Filipino, Jewish, and Hungarian ancestry; parents' emphasis on an affluent, "old world Europe" identity; perspectives on race and social justice; and involvement in political activism, particularly with the Occupy movement in New York City. Interview conducted Manissa Maharawal.
  Oral history with Zoltan Gluck's partner, Manissa Maharawal, 2011.019.093.
  Budapest (Hungary); Community activists |z New York (State) |z New York; Education, Higher |z New York (State); Interracial dating; Mexican Americans |z California; Occupy movement |z New York (State) |z New York; Privilege; Race identity; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; San Francisco (Calif.)
- Itamar Goldstein, 2011 December 9; 2011.019.004
  Itamar Goldstein was born to a Yemenite Jewish mother and an American Jewish father in Jerusalem, Israel. Goldstein served in the Israeli army as a young adult and moved to Brooklyn, New York to attend medical school at the State University of New York Downstate Medical Center in New York City.
  In the interview, Goldstein discusses his childhood; travel experiences; service in the Israeli army; experiences as an Israeli Jew living in in New York City; impressions of the Arab-Israeli conflict; and the distinct religious, cultural, and linguistic practices of Yemenite Jews and other Jewish ethnic groups in Israel. Interview conducted by Katrina Grigg-Saito.
  Arab-Israeli conflict; Education, Higher |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Israel; Israelis |z New York (State) |z New York; Jerusalem; Jews, Yemenite |z Israel; Judaism; Palestine
- Paul Golin and Yurika Golin, 2013 August 16; 2011.019.052
  Paul Golin was born to Jewish American parents and raised in Staten Island, New York. He attended the University of Michigan at Ann Arbor and worked for the Jewish Outreach Institute, an organization dedicated to serving unaffiliated and interfaith Jewish families in New York City.
  Yurika Golin was born to Japanese parents and raised in Tokyo, Japan. She attended Kingsborough Community College and Baruch College, both located in New York City. She worked as a flight attendant with Continental Airlines and United Airlines.
  In the interviews, Paul and Yurika discuss their courtship and marriage; negotiations surrounding cultural backgrounds; and exposing their son to his linguistic and religious heritage. Paul discusses race and diversity in Brooklyn; gentrification; and interracial relationships. Yurika discusses her experience of moving to New York City a few weeks before the September 11 Terrorist Attacks. Interviews conducted by Abigail Ettelman.
  Education, Higher |z New York (State) |z New York; Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945); Interfaith families; Japanese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Jews, Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Judaism; Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Racially mixed families; September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001; Tokyo (Japan); United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Leslie Gordon, 2013 May 12; 2011.019.046
  Leslie Gordon was born to a white American Jewish mother and a mixed race American father in Berkeley, California. Gordon received a B.A. in political science from the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. She lived in New York City and worked as a development associate for Education Through Music, a nonprofit organization dedicated to bringing music programs to inner city schools.
  In the interview, Gordon discusses her racial identity; interracial relationships; impressions of cultural diversity in the San Francisco Bay Area; parents' courtship and marriage; father's African American, Native American, and German heritage; and impressions of family businesses founded by her grandparents. Interview conducted by Jonathan Tarleton.
  Berkeley (Calif.); Cultural diversity; Education |z California |z Berkeley; Education, Higher |z North Carolina |z Chapel Hill; Race identity; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people
- Dina Helal, 2013 July 19; 2013 October 20; 2011.019.061
  Dina Helal was born to an Ashkenazi Jewish mother and an Egyptian father in London, England. Helal received a B.A. in art and art history from the University of Leeds in England and an M.F.A. in painting from Pratt Institute in New York City. She worked as the manager of education resources at the Whitney Museum of Art in Manhattan, New York.
  In the interview, Helal discusses her childhood; racial identity; parents' marriage and divorce; involvement in New York City's artistic community; relationship with her partner; death of her partner and parents; and experiences living in the Greenpoint neighborhood of Brooklyn. Interview conducted by Liza Zapol.
  Artists |z New York (State) |z New York; Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.); Bereavement; England |x Emigration and immigration; Greenpoint (New York, N.Y.); Interfaith families; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001; United States |x Emigration and immigration; Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.)
- Lisa Heller, 2011 December 20; 2011.019.008
  Lisa Heller, who has African American and American Jewish heritage, was raised in the Bronx, New York. Heller received a B.A. in economic geography from the University of California at Berkeley and a dual M.B.A./M.C.P. from the Sloan School of Management at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in Boston, Massachusetts.
  In the interview, Heller discusses her racial identity and appearance; childhood in a white Jewish household; decision to become a single mother; and presentation of her son's racial identity and heritage. Interview conducted by Jen Chau.
  African American Jews |z New York (State) |z New York; Education, Higher |z California |z Berkeley; Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.); Race identity; Racially mixed people; Religious identity; Single mothers |z New York (State) |z New York
- Lyn Hill, 2013 August 22; 2011.019.057
  Lyn Hill was born to German Jewish parents and raised in Queens, New York. Hill received a B.A. and an M.A. from Queens College, and a Ph.D. from the Graduate Center at City University of New York, both located in New York City. She worked as a costume designer, theatre educator and historian, and hospital administrator.
  In the interview, Hill discusses her childhood in the Inwood and Forest Hills neighborhoods of Queens; courtship and marriage to her Christian husband; parents' flight from Nazi Germany; career in theater and costume design; and suffering from Graves' Disease, an immune system disorder. Interview conducted by Abigail Ettelman.
  Christians |z New York (State) |z New York; Education |z New York (State) |z New York; Forest Hills (New York, N.Y.); Graves' disease; Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945); Interfaith families; Interfaith marriage; Inwood (New York, N.Y.); Jews, American |z New York (State) |z Queens County; Jews, German |z New York (State) |z Queens County; Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Theaters |z New York (State)
- Lenge Hong, 2012 January 19; 2011.019.014
  Lenge Hong was born to a Scottish mother and a Chinese father and raised in Miami, Florida. Hong received a B.F.A. in film and video production from New York University, an M.F.A. in creative writing from the New School, and an M.L.S. from Pratt Institute, all located in New York City. She worked as a film researcher and as an archivist at the New York Historical Society in New York City.
  In the interview, Hong discusses her family; racial identity and racially ambiguous appearance; educational experiences; career path; father's immigration to the United States from China; and the history of media portrayals of mixed race people. Interview conducted by Jen Chau.
  China; Chinese Americans |z Florida |z Miami; Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Education, Higher |z New York (State) |z New York; Miami (Fla.); Race identity; Racially ambiguous people; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Racism in mass media; Scottish Americans |z Florida |z Miami; United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Minna Aslama Horowitz, 2013 December 13; 2011.019.072
  Minna Aslama Horowitz was born to Finnish parents in Finland. Horowitz received a Ph.D. from the University of Helsinki in Finland and immigrated to the United States to work as a fellow for the Social Science Research Council in New York City. She was employed an assistant professor of mass communication in the College of Professional Studies at St. John’s University in New York City.
  In the interview, Horowitz discusses her experiences living in the Crown Heights and Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhoods of Brooklyn; relationship with her husband, a Russian American Jew from Brooklyn, New York; and impressions of the differences between Finnish and American culture in regards to academia, economic security, and community identity. Interview conducted by Liza Zapol.
  Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.); Community identity |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.); Cultural diversity; Education, Higher |z New York (State) |z New York; Finland; Finns |z New York (State) |z New York; Interethnic marriage; United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Aya Hosch, 2013 December 10; 2011.019.071